<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>AL Lint on Stefan Maron blog</title>
    <link>https://stefanmaron.onrender.com/tags/al-lint/</link>
    <description>Recent content in AL Lint on Stefan Maron blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 08:00:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://stefanmaron.onrender.com/tags/al-lint/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bugfixes for LinterCop Rule LC0015</title>
      <link>https://stefanmaron.onrender.com/posts/bugfixes-for-lintercop-rule-lc0015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 08:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stefanmaron.onrender.com/posts/bugfixes-for-lintercop-rule-lc0015/</guid>
      <description>I just released a new version for the BusinessCentral.LinterCop.
This rule is similar to the PTE0004 from Microsoft which checks for your tables to have a TableData permission set. All the other permissions are not covered.
After some discussion and some thoughts I ended up also including the check for TableData in LC0015. If you dont want to have a double check for this, you can disable PTE0004.
More details can be found in the dedicated docs side for this rule:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Business Central LinterCop with older Versions of BC</title>
      <link>https://stefanmaron.onrender.com/posts/business-central-lintercop-with-older-versions-of-bc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 05:37:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stefanmaron.onrender.com/posts/business-central-lintercop-with-older-versions-of-bc/</guid>
      <description>If you want to run pipelines with the LinterCop, you can use Run-ALPipeline and pass in the path to the LinterCop.dll via the parameter - CustomCops. But when running pipelines for various versions of BusinessCentral you might encounter errors like this:
Microsoft.Dynamics.Nav.CodeAnalysis, Version=8.2.8.24543, Culture=neutral, PublicKeyToken=31bf3856ad364e35&#39;(,): warning : An instance of analyzer http://BusinessCentral.LinterCop.Design.Rule0012DoNotUseObjectIdInSystemFunctions cannot be created from C:\Agent\LinterCop\BusinessCentral.LinterCop.dll : Could not load file or assembly &#39;Microsoft.Dynamics.Nav.CodeAnalysis, Version=8.2.8.24543, Culture=neutral, PublicKeyToken=31bf3856ad364e35&#39;. The system cannot find the file specified.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BusinessCentral.LinterCop goes VS Code!</title>
      <link>https://stefanmaron.onrender.com/posts/businesscentral-lintercop-goes-vs-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 15:59:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stefanmaron.onrender.com/posts/businesscentral-lintercop-goes-vs-code/</guid>
      <description>After quite some analyzing and reverse engineering, I got it working!
The custom code analyzer BusinessCentral.LinterCop is running included in VS Code.
And here is how to do it: First, go to my GitHub and download the latest binary here.
Then just place it on your hard drive, for example &amp;ldquo;C:\ALCustomCops\&amp;rdquo;
Then go to your settings file and insert it in the &amp;ldquo;al.codeAnalyzers&amp;rdquo; like this:
And thats it! Pretty short Blog but this should get you going ;)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AL Lint v0.1.7: Code Metrics</title>
      <link>https://stefanmaron.onrender.com/posts/al-lint-v0-1-7-code-metrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 06:09:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stefanmaron.onrender.com/posts/al-lint-v0-1-7-code-metrics/</guid>
      <description>This morning I updated the code metrics calculation in AL Lint. Code metrics are meant to give you some comparable numbers on how complex your code is.
Why is this important information?
In general, if you install this extension, you aim for clean code. This is because code is written once but probably is read multiple times. And the easier it is to understand the more time you will save while reading your code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VS Code extension: AL Lint</title>
      <link>https://stefanmaron.onrender.com/posts/vs-code-extension-al-lint/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 13:34:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stefanmaron.onrender.com/posts/vs-code-extension-al-lint/</guid>
      <description>Maybe you have read this in twitter already: I took over the AL Lint extension for VS Code from Marije Brummel. She searched quite some time already for someone and finally she found me :D
For now I did two things on this extension for now.
 I worked myself a little bit into extension development for VS Code and did a little bit of refactoring, updated some dependencies to new versions and removed checks which are now covered by the AL Code Cops.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
